Guide to the Naomi Shihab Nye Papers
The Wittliff Collections
- Works, 1963-2017; 30 boxes
  - Notebooks, 1972-circa 2010
    - Before 1980 (Box 4, Folder 2)
      Poems and drafts. 10 pages. Includes draft of "Different Ways to Pray," "Still Waiting on a Dull Moment," and notes on instruction.
    - July 4, 1980 - circa February 23, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 3)
      "Traveling Journal-California July 4-6, 1980 - Additional Na Bolom notes 1985." Notes for story "Pablo," poem draft "Gabriel," draft story "Camel Like Only Camel," extensive notes labeled "Peter Mattheissen, Trinity, Feb. 23 '98," and some notes labeled "Coleman Barks UTSA, Feb, 1998." 23 pages.
    - "Summer 1980, Honduras", July 23, 1980 - August 1980 (Box 4, Folder 4)
      Journal entries, "Notes for 'Maestro,'" laid in poem draft "Black Beans." 53 pages.
    - "Vermont", July 1984 (Box 4, Folder 5)
      Journal entries and class notes, transcribed poems, poem drafts, "Gabriel," "After the Party," "Promise," "Invisible," "Night Blooming Cereus," "Taking Care of What We Love," and others. Notes for talk "Arizona." 29 pages.
    - December 23, 1984 - April 8, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 6)
      Diary entries for Nepal, Cairo, and Palestine, including family visits, and Delhi, India; sketch, notes on camels, "memorable characters." Poem drafts "San Cristobal," "Camel Like Only Camel," and prose "Mister Potato," and list of "homes enroute." 71 pages.
    - "Na Bolom-San Cristobál de Las Casas, Chiapas, Mexico, July - August 1985 AND Baby Notes, Spring '86", Summer 1985, Spring 1986 (Box 4, Folder 7)
      Diary entries, poem drafts "Blue Bucket," notes on Pat Mora's reading in San Antonio. 76 pages.
    - Circa April 22 - circa November 28, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 8)
      Notes, recipe, journal entries in Maine, poem draft "A Definite Shore," "The Endless Indian Nights," "Tea Seller, Rajasthan," "Winter in Your Part of the World," "At Mother Theresa's," "Eureka Springs, Arkansas," "Arizona," "Corsicana," "Call Me Ben," journal entries in Texas, "Thunder," Cuernavaca, Mexico, "Frida Kahlo's House," Philadelphia Arts Alliance, Denver, and others. 60 pages.
    - September 17, 1987 - May 1, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 9)
      Journal entries from San Cristóbal, poem drafts "Mercado," "Blue Island of Old Friends," "The Hidden Heart of Mexico," journal entry after father's surgery, "From Bangalore," "The Length of Red Tape," "Merwin's Wall," "Beyond the Kitchen Window," journal entries on traveling, " Aziz Meets a Bear Near Cloudcroft, New Mexico," "Where Nye, Oregon Isn't Anymore." 76 pages.
    - March 12 - August 4, 1991 and March 11, 1992 - undated (Box 4, Folder 10)
      Journal entries New York City, poem drafts throughout, laid-in poems by others, Kim Stafford workshop notes from Our Lady of the Lake, sketched map of Nye's neighborhood, "Arts Magnet" notes, El Paso Community College workshop and elementary school workshop notes, About 120 pages.
    - September 8 - November 20, 1991 and circa April 11, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 11)
      Laid in annotated poetry writing workshop outline; journal entries from Hawai'i; Bonassi poem "One Hammer;" Madison Nye poem "Healed;" many annotated poem drafts; "The Burning House," "Violin," "School bell," and "Faces Under Occupation. About 120 pages.
    - November 28, 1991 - November 25, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 12)
      Annotated poem drafts. Sections titled "Thanksgiving at [W.S.] Merwin's," "Cairo," "Jordan," "Essay/letters to Alix," Rochester, Scranton PA, "Notes for Piece for Anton." Journal entries from Jerusalem. About 70 pages.
    - May, 1992 - circa December 1992, undated (Box 4, Folder 13)
      First notes and lines of "Maintenance," annotated poem drafts, notes for reading and workshop. About 100 pages.
    - January 2, 1993 - circa November 19, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 1)
      Labeled "1993 Notebook." Annotated poems, journal entries. About 50 pages.
    - Circa March 22 - April 13, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 2)
      Notes for readings, journal entries in Jerusalem, annotated poems. About 100 pages.
    - Circa 1993, February 1998, and undated (Box 5, Folder 3)
      Poems, notes, notes on other's readings. About 30 pages.
    - "Journeys Book / notes / further notes", circa November 6, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 4)
      Notes for poems. 4 pages.
    - July - December 2000 (Box 5, Folder 5)
      Notes in Scotland, Maryland, "Florrie notes," "The Gift of West Texas," notes, poems, children's drawings and games, 19 pages. Small bound notebook 'The San Miguel Poetry Week.'
    - Circa 2000-2003 (Box 5, Folder 6)
      Notes, poems, notes for readings including "Why do we need poetry more than ever?" 13 pages.
    - Circa 2002 (Box 49, Folder 3)
      Poem drafts, including "Peace Talks," "My Geography," "Three Mule Deer."
    - Circa 2007 (Box 5, Folder 7)
      Notes for reading "Life Lines," poem "To Dad," notes on event at Incarnate Word Chapel. 17 pages.
    - December 17, 2007 - circa April 3, 2008 (Box 5, Folder 8)
      Story about Tommy Lee Jones; journal entries in Muscat, Oman, visit to mother's house, Utah, notes on Seymour Hersh on George W. Bush, poem pieces, several "For Daddy" poems. 68 pages.
    - October 18, 2010 - circa 2010 (Box 5, Folder 9)
      Journal entries in Pennsylvania, New York, notes from Larry Wright event. 31 pages.
    - Undated (Box 5, Folder 10)
      Notes, poems and fragments, sketches, journal entries. 32 pages.
    - Canada travel, undated (Box 5, Folder 11)
      Travel notes and dates, addresses, poems "Montreal," "Good Morning I am an American Shut Up," "Enough for a Pie," "Our Daily Conversations," notes and "Moments," "While I was in Canada," small sketches. 60 pages.
    - "Hawai'i", undated (Box 5, Folder 12)
      Notes on travel plans and events, addresses, one poem "Song for Christmas." 25 pages.
    - Undated (Box 49, Folder 4)
      Oversized. Class exercises, assignments and ideas, notes related to her poems, examples, list of songs for class use. 26 pages.
    - Undated (Box 5, Folder 13)
      Poem drafts
    - Undated (Box 5, Folder 14)
      Drafts "Golf Tee is Not Me," and "To the IRS," notes.
    - Undated (Box 5, Folder 15)
      Poetry Workshop, "Aleppo," vita/bio notes, notes.
  - Appointment Books, 1988 - 2015, undated (Box 5, Folder 16, Box 6, Folder 1, Box 49, Folder 5)
  - Artwork, 1969-1973, undated
    - Apple Print, 1969
      Robert E. Lee high school work.
    - Watercolors, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 3)
      Trinity University course.
    - Drawings, undated (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Early Work, 1959-1980, undated
    - "A Story Book", 1959 (Box 49, Folder 6)
      Illustrated handmade book of poetry, Central School, Ferguson, Missouri. 21 pages.
    - High school writing, 1966-1970
      Poetry and short stories. 12 pages.
    - Young Pegasus, 1969-1970
      Includes published poems, "Jerusalem" and "Translucence."
    - College writing, 1970-1974
      Poetry, short stories, play, assignments. Includes drafts of later works. [2 folders]
    - College Notebook, circa 1974
      Includes class notes and poems.
    - "Packing Lunches for the World", 1980, undated
      15 pages including 3 handwritten drafts and 1 publication.
    - "The True Love", undated
      19 pages; 4 drafts, typed and handwritten.
    - "Unlimited Visibility, or Rosie in the Sky", undated
      Handwritten notebook.
    - Short prose pieces, undated
      5 pieces, typed and handwritten.
    - "The Autobiography", undated (Box 7, Folder 1)
      100 handwritten and typed pages.
    - "Those Zen Masters Were No Fools", undated (Box 7, Folder 2)
      154 handwritten and typed pages.
    - "I Always Broke My Toys", undated (Box 7, Folder 3)
      Screenplay draft, 16 handwritten pages. Draft, 7 typed pages.
    - Trinity Review, undated (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Music, 1979-1981, undated
    - Albums, 1979-1981 (Box 49, Folder 7)
      Rutabaga-Roo: I've Got a Song and It's for You, 1979. Long-playing record., Rutabaga-Roo, circa 1979. Promotional poster and 45 rpm record sleeve. Lullaby Raft, 1981. Long-playing record.
    - Rutabaga-Roo Poster, 1979 (Box 54, Folder 1)
    - Audiocassettes, 1979-1981 (Box 7, Folder 5)
      Audiocassette containing Rutabaga-Roo and Lullaby Raft. Audiocassette of Lullaby Raft.
    - Songs, circa 1978-1980, undated
      - A-B (Box 7, Folder 6)
        "The Albany Song," "Aleppo Song," "Amigo of the City - Henry B. [Henry Barrientos]," "And I Don't Know if It's Possible," "And if I came to See you Now," "The Ants Dance," "Anyway," "April's Creed," "The Ballad of Empty Hook," "Balloon," "Behind the Blind," "Believer From a Long Way Back," "Beloved, I listen hard through all the quiet days," "Beloved, we've traveled far through all the distant days," "Blue," "Board of Trustees," "The Breaking of Blue," "Bridge cross the river," "Bridge over the Harbor."
      - C-D (Box 7, Folder 7)
        "Can't Complain," "Chicken Song," "Christmas Song," "The Circus Song," "Comanche means enemy," "Come and Go," "The Contradictions Song," "The Corpus Christi Song," "Dandelion Blower Blues (and Whites)," "Days Like This," "The Different One," "Don't Worry About Alonzo," "Doors, Doors," "Doubt Song," "Dubby's Song."
      - E-H (Box 7, Folder 8)
        "Everybody's Got These Folks," "Everything High," "First- Class Party," "Flames on the hillside," "Florida," "For a long time I have loved the sea," "For the Gulls all Up and Down," "The Friend Song," "Gonna get me a husband," "Goodbye Song," "Grocery Store Raga," "The Hat Song," "Henry's Song - For H.D. Thoreau," "Heroes in the Dime Store," "Hey Mama," "Hit the Road," "Hondo's Lament," "How Was I to Know," "Hurricane."
      - I-J (Box 7, Folder 9)
        "I Can Be a Loner Pretty Well," "I found you on the outskirts of the country in my soul," "I Got Wheels," "I saw the sun," "I Was Blue," "I was born on the prairie," "I was cashing a check," "If I cannot love you now," "If I Sang," "It's a desert," "Just Like a Recurring Dream."
      - K-L (Box 7, Folder 10)
        "Kerry's Song," "Kingsville Auction Song," "Lady sang a song," "Lately I've had questions," "Little Blanco River," "Lonesome Weaver," "The Losing Song," "Lost in Austin," "Lover of the Light," "Lullaby Raft."
      - M-N (Box 7, Folder 11)
        "Meditation," "More Like Me," "Mostly now my dreams have been serene," "My body is a mystery," "My closet is a little place," "My Heart is Torn Like a Chicken Bone in Two," "My Song," "New Year Song," "Nice," "No Inclinations," "Nobody Home," "Nobody Thinks of Dying in the Middle of the Day."
      - O-P (Box 7, Folder 12)
        "Old Lost Song," "Old - New," "Old Songs," "On the Brink," "Only You," "Pat & Julie's Song."
      - Q-R (Box 7, Folder 13)
        "Questions," "Ragamuffin Blue Blues Crying Song," The river is deeper than the puddle in the street," "Rosie took a ship across the sea," "The Rutabaga Song."
      - S (Box 7, Folder 14)
        "San Antonio Song," "San Antonio--The City of Hearts," "Second in a New Chapter of Thousands," "Seeds," "Shoes Blues," "Solitary Man," "Somewhere in the Greens," "Song for All Those People Who Have a Be Here Now Book Covered with Dust on a Shelf," "Song for Dick Poteet," "Song for John Walters," "Song for Max," "Song for Townes [Van Zandt]," "Sunday morning very bright I read your book," "Sweet Creek."
      - T-U (Box 7, Folder 15)
        "Tell me," "Ten Bears," "The Texas Torch," "There are highways stretching endlessly," "There is a small house that hides in the hills," "Those Eyes," "To all the teachers I was mean to," "Two Days Now," "The Unbroken Circle They Sing About," "Uncle Frank's Song."
      - W (Box 7, Folder 16)
        "Walkin with you on a Sunday," "Walking Out," "Watching You When You're Not Looking," "The Way It Is, The Way It Used to Be," "We Are the Ones," "We will gather all the pieces," "Well the sun is surely sinkin down," "Wheels," "When All is Said and Done, He Is," "When I see your face," "When I Wake up in the Morning," "When I was Born," "When I was Lost," "When You're Not Looking," "Willow willow will ya be my friend?," "Wishes."
      - Y (Box 7, Folder 17)
        "You are a Quiet Song," "You are Someone," "You Came Through," "You can call this what you like," "Your words are slippery."
      - Multiple Songs (Box 7, Folder 18)
        Final drafts of "The Albany Song," "Behind the Blind," "John's Song," "You are a Quiet Song," "Corpus Christi Song," "Henry's Song," "The Circus Song," "Rosie," "Just Like a Recurring Dream," "Banjo Man," "When I Wake in the Morning."
      - Other (Box 7, Folder 19)
        Notes, Fragments, Setlists and performance notes, Contract and promotion, Songs by others.
  - Poems, circa 1970s - circa 2010s
    - A (Box 7, Folder 20)
      "Abandoned Post Office, Big Bend, Texas," "Above the Weather," "Acrostic," "Acupuncture," "The Address Book of a Lonely Man," "Adios," "After Being Recognized at the Museum," "After Everything," "After Him Everything Changed," "After School," "Air," "The Air Inside Each Car," "Aleppo," "Alice," "All day long a poem has been coming and here it is," "All Our Early Words," "All We Will Not Know – for Adriana Corral," "Allah Sees You Whip the Dog," "Alma Mater," "Alphabet," "Am I your horizon," "Amir & Anna," "And Here We Are," "And What About Two Seagulls Flying Parallel," "Anger," "Another Summer," "Answering Your Letter," "Any Number," "Anything Can Happen - And It Does," "Appetite," "Arabic Room," "The Archaeologist Eating Breakfast," "Archive," "Arizona," "Arizona - for James and Nancy," "The Arlyne Theater Has Been Torn Down, Longview, Texas," "The Art of Disappearing," "An Assigned Poem on the Devil or Why High School Students Often Hate Poetry," "At Last, A Smile," "At Last, For Becky," "At the Fair in Chimaltenango," "At the Jungle," "At the McKenzie River," "At the Pacific," "Atlanta," "Audience," "Aurora Borealis."
    - B (Box 8, Folder 1)
      "Baby," "Baby," "Bad Moon," "Back in the City of My Birth (St. Louis, March 22, 1973)," "Bangalore," "Because of poems," "Bed," "The Bells, Longview, Texas 4:30 p.m. Sept. 18, 1974," "Beyond All This," "Beyond This World There Are Twenty Other Worlds," "Bingo!," "Bir Zeit, Palestine," "Birthday - for Jack Kerouac," "Birthday," "The Blanco Cafe Burning," "Blanket of bygones is too heavy for this season," "Blessings on our Early Minds," "Blood," "Blood on All Your Shirts," "The Body in the Street," "Books We Haven't Touched in Years," "Borrowed Vehicles," "The Boy Instructs His Mother," "The Boy Removes All Traces of Childhood from His Room," "A boy stands with his hands in his pockets," "The Brick," "Brief Comment About 'Marie'," "The Burglar's Hand," "Burlington, Vermont," "Burning," "The Burning House," "Burning the Old Year."
    - C (Box 8, Folder 2)
      "California Time, Texas Time," "Calling You or Borders," "Canoeing with Alligators," "The Car Wash," "Cat," "Catalogue Army," "Cello," "Changed," "Changing My Name," "Chiapas," "Chula," "Clarence," "Clean Slate," "Clearing the Look of Worry Off My Face," "The Closest to a Love Poem I'm Ever Going to Get (I Bet)," "Coming Home to Myself," "Coming to See the Marfa Lights, Marfa, Texas," "Coming Up for Air - to M.B.," "Companions," "Compass," "Concrete," "Consider his own tall house– For Ryushin Paul Haller," "Conversation on Ironing," "Conversations to be Packed for Travel," "Correspondence," "Courage," "Cowboys and Librarians," "Cross that Line," "Cursive."
    - D (Box 8, Folder 3)
      "Dallas Suburban," "Dark," "Darling," "The Day," "The Day of Randy's Funeral," "Days We Are Mad with One Another," "Dead Bees," "The Death of a Cat," "Debris," "Delivering Poems Books to the Housing Projects, Victoria Courts, San Antonio," "Desert David's Song," "The Deserted Yard," "Different Ways to Pray," "Dinner Party," "The Dirtiest 4-Letter Word," "Disappointment," "Disarmed," "Donuts," "A Door," "Door to Door," "The Dream Bakery Poems," "Dressing like an Indian," "Drive Friendly," "Driving North from Kingsville, Texas," "Dropping a Line," "Dying."
    - E (Box 8, Folder 4)
      "Easy Terms," "Eating in Berkeley," "The Edge of a Country," "8 Oh Clock," "The Endless Indian Nights," "Enough," "Envy," "Escape," "The Essential Month of July," "Estate Sale: The Scrabble Game of a Dead Woman," "The Esteemed Writer Never Reads Poetry (after hearing Philip Roth)," "Even the Crackers," "The evening sky was as purple as a newly squashed grape," "Every Cat Had a Story," "Every War Looks Good on Paper Until You Meet the Enemy."
    - Faces-For the First Time (Box 8, Folder 5)
      "Faces," "Faces Coming Out of Carnegie Hall," "Fair forlorn," "Fairbanks, Alaska," "Family Love," "Far away up north my grandpa is dying," "Farewell to a Robin," "February," "February," "La Feria," "Fifty Years," "The First Poem I Ever Wrote," "First Things Last," "The First Time I Was Old," "Fixing a Russian Watch," "Flow," "Fluency - for Anthony Villarreal," "Foot in the Village," "For Aziz, Who Loved Jerusalem," "For Bob Bonazzi Who Says the Literal World Is in Order," "For Carmon Who Told Me Tonight I Beat Around the Bush," "For David, in Canada," "For days now there has been no wind," "For Dubby Who Said, 'What I Would Like to Know Is, How Can Everybody Be Gone When There Was Never Anybody Here?'," "For J.W. Who Never Used His Real Name," "For Lost and Found Brothers," "For Luke, Leaving Us," "For Grandma Marie, Who Has Been Mostly Forgotten," "For Nancy who said, 'Maybe you need some time to catch up on your writing.,'" "For Nelle, Years Later (Los Chupaderos Ranch)," "For Mohammed on the Mountain," "For Mrs. Lane of Second Grade," "For My Father Who Always Thinks I Have Been Somewhere I Haven't," "For My Parents Leaving the Country," "For Our Father's Lost Businesses," "For Palestine and for Israel," "For Robert at Halloween," "For Somebody Who Has Trouble Being in a Body," "For Susan," "For the First Time He Says…."
    - For the Gulls-Future (Box 8, Folder 6)
      "For the Gulls All Up and Down," "For the Man at the Counter in the Steak and Egg Restaurant, 19th Street, Austin, Texas, 16 March 1975, 10:30 p.m.," "For the Parents of Dror and Hassan / A Young Jew & Young Egyptian / Killed in Action," "For the Poets of Dhaka," "For years the vine grew steadily," "4-Way Traffic," "Four Poems of the Pink Swing," "Free," "French Movies," "A Friend Dies in Houston," "The Friend Who Let Me Go," "A Friend's Welcome," "Friendly Postal Clerk, Saturday Morning," "The Frogs Did Not Forget," "From the Air," "From Here to There," "From Labrador, 1800's," "From Texas," "Fundamentalism," "Future."
    - G (Box 8, Folder 7)
      "Gabriel Street," "The Gardener," "Gate 4-A," "Gather Together," "Genoveva," "The Getting Together," "Gifts," "The Girl at the Swimming Pool," "The Girl Who Did Not Treasure Words," "Glaciers," "A Glad Poem or Lots of Times No Whys Is Wise," "God's Body, Not My Body," "Going for Peaches, Fredericksburg, 1981," "Going On," "Good Morning[SK1]," "Goodby," "Goodby," "Grandfather's Heaven," "Grandpa's Coat," "The Grapefruit," "Grateful," "The Great Photographer Has His Picture Taken," "Gripping Avocados to Stay Sane," "Growing," and "Growing up in Missouri," "Guide."
    - H (Box 8, Folder 8)
      "The Hair," "Hairdo," "Half a Thousand Miles with You," "Hands Touching Each Other," "hang-ups have many drawbacks," "Harvey Street," "Have You Ever Had a Little Rocking Chair in Your Heart - for Kerry Crouch," "Having Been Lonesome for the Last Six Days," "He Has a New Plan," "The Head That Follows My Mother," "Hearts," "Heirs," "Hello," "Hello, Palestine," "Her Papers, After Her Death," "Here is what I know, it is not much," "High Hopes," "History of Getting Older," "Home," "Home Again," "Hospitality," "How?," "How and Why the Heart Cries b& For What Reason," "How do I know when a poem is finished?," "How It Is," "How Long Peace Takes," "How Palestinians Keep Warm," "How Things Connect," "How to Get to My House," "How to Paint a Donkey," "How to Recognize Middle C, For Chula," "A Human Poem."
    - I (Box 8, Folder 9)
      "I," "I am a hooligan," "I Could Not Curse the Hook," "I Feel Sorry for Jesus," "I have no inclination to eat sweets anymore," "I look into Virginia," "I move inside the slow breathing," "I need," "I Tell Myself the Following Story," "I was thinking of Poems," "Ideas Do Not Go Far in the Wilderness," "If Sadness Had a Head," "If You Just Start Drawing You Don't Know Where It's Going to End Up," "In Real Life," "In Unison," "Instructions Number One," "Instructions Number Two," "Intensive Care," "Interview, Saudi Arabia," "Invisible," "Invitation to Restlessness," "Island," "It's Everywhere," "It's Hallie Stillwell's Birthday and What Can We Give Her?."
    - J-K (Box 8, Folder 10)
      "Jack Kerouac's Will," "January's Clean Bright Cap," "Jay's Dog Naomi," "Jefferson, Texas," "Jerusalem," "Jerusalem Headlines 2000," "Jesse the Cat," "Jesus is the King of Cuero," "Jordan's Blizzard," "The Journey of Pablo Tamayo," "July Fourth," "July 9, 1970," "June 26, 1995," "Kansas (for Michael)," "Kindness," "The King's Highway," "Knitting, Crocheting, Sewing…."
    - La Conner-Lights (Box 8, Folder 11)
      "La Conner, Prayer," "Labrador," "Last August Hours before the Year 2000," "Late," "Late in Life He Realizes His One True Love Has Been a Broom," "Lately all I write is Going-poems," "Leaning Toward Mecca - for my father," "Learning to Walk on the Hardest Floor," "Leaving Antigua," "Leaving the Park," "Leaving Pittsburgh - for Samuel Hazo and Pat Truschel," "Lena," "The Length of Red Tape," "Leo," "The Letter," "A Letter to My Mother," "Letters," "Letters My Prez Is Not Sending," "Lexicon," "Library," "Life Story," "Light & Stones: The Viewing of an Exhibit, for Mona Sau'di," "The Light Where Lives Intercept," "Lights from Other Windows," "Lights on the Loop."
    - Like-Lure (Box 8, Folder 12)
      "Like a spectator at a football game," "Linked," undated, "Little Blanco River," "Little Boy Calling Mama," "Little Neighborhood Things," "The Little Pitcher," "Live Models," "Lives of the Women Poets," "Living Alone Inside One's Own Body," "Living at the Airport," "Living Where We Do," "Living With Art," "Lizard," "Lobster Knocking on the Lid of a Pan," "Locusts' Lament," "The Loneliness of Having a Baby," "Long Distance," "Longview County Fair," "Long Match," "Lookout Mountain, Chattanooga Tennessee," "Losing at Marbles," "Losing My Wisest Tooth," "Lost Creed," "Love Letter, Hate Letter," "Lucia, Your Voice," "Luggage," "Lunch Box," "Lunch in Nablus City Park," "Lure."
    - Mad-Migrating (Box 8, Folder 13)
      "Mad," "Made of Wood," "Magician," "Magnetic Poetry Kit," "Mail," "Maître D'," "Making a Fist," "The Man Who Hated Trees," "The Man Who Makes Brooms, Jerusalem, 1983," "The Man Who Quoted Thoreau in the Laundromat," "The Man Who Screamed in His House," "The Man Who Steals Newspapers," "The Many Hats of William Yale," "Map," "Margaret," "Marilyn," "Marriage," "Martita y Luisa," "Maui—In Trade," "Max," "Meat," "Meditation," "Memphis – for Carmon," "Message," "Message in the thin wind before bedtime," "Mexican Food in Vermont: for Geof Hewitt," "Mexico at Age 7," "Migrating."
    - Mine-Mystery (Box 8, Folder 14)
      "Mine," "Minnows," "Missing Me, Wish I Were Here," "Missing the Indians," "Morning on South Main," "Mother of Nothing," "My Body is a Mystery," "My Cosmic Poem – for Craig," "My Father and the Figtree," "My Grandmother Has Tattooed Feet," "My Grandmother in the Stars," "My Little Blue Plant," "My Neighbor at 98," "My President Went," "My turtle curls inside her walls," "My Two Machines," "Mysteries," "The Mystery," "The Mystery."
    - N (Box 8, Folder 15)